《黑镜》
《暗黑博物馆》
∮ 我生来就是要爱你 ∮
∮ I was born to love you ∮
∮ 我永远无法解脱 ∮
∮ And I will never be free ∮
∮ 你会永远是我的一部分 ∮
∮ You'll always be a part of me ∮
（充电需时 03：11：48）
（暗黑博物馆）
（开展时间 上午11点）
11点才开 你最早 今天人一定很多
Tours begin at 11. You're the first in line. Could be a busy day.
大道上没什么人啊
Road seemed pretty empty.
口音挺带劲 澳大利亚人
Nice accent. You from Australia?
不是 英国人
No, I'm from Britain.
那你八成叫那种特拗口的英式名字吧
So you got one of those crazy British names?
艾丝美拉达之类的
Esmeralda or, uh…?
我就叫妮什
I'm Nish.
- 就妮什 - 妮什
- Nish? - Nish.
我也没资格说你 我的名字就特逗
Well, I can't judge. My name's ridiculous.
罗洛·海恩斯 馆主兼业主
Rolo Haynes. Owner. Proprietor.
看来今早就咱俩 你确定想进去看看吗
Well, just us two this morning. You sure you wanna do this?
心脏不强大的可受不了
This place ain't for the faint-hearted.
我想我应该能应付得来
I'm sure I can handle it.
不是所有人都能
Not everyone can.
可以的话我得看看你包里都装了什么
So, I have to peek in your little sack there if that's OK.
- 可以 - 这年头谁都不能不防
- That's OK. - Can't trust anyone these days.
还得麻烦你从那里过一下
If you could step through there.
金属的东西都装在盒子里
Anything metal, put it in here.
好
Cool.
挺炫啊
Dinky.
我称之为袖珍机
Oh, yeah. I call it fun size.
袖珍 我喜欢
Fun size. I like that.
你在机场过安检肯定耗了好半天吧
Guessing you had a gut full of this security shit at the airport.
这年头移民局的人可严了
Our immigration guys are pretty tight these days.
检查好了吗
All clear?
好了
Ok.
开始表演吧
Show on the road.
你这是放假了
So, you on vacation?
算是吧 我爸在这一带住
Sort of. My dad lives out here.
今天是他生日 所以我妈想给他个惊喜
It's his birthday, so my mom just wants to surprise him.
惊喜就是你吗
And you're the surprise?
一部分吧
part of it, I guess.
- 你从哪飞过来的 - 盐湖城
- Where'd you fly in? - Salt Lake.
你从盐湖城赶过来的
You came here from Salt Lake?
我本来打算走走荒野大公路
Yeah, I thought it'd be nice to drive the back route,
但我低估了…
but I underestimated the…
这条路可不适合姑娘家自己走啊
Heck of a trip for a girl on her own.
- 我不是有意拿老眼光看你 - 不是吧
- I don't mean to get old-fashioned on you. - Seriously?
你这看法确实够老套的
That is quite old-fashioned.
这里热得跟地狱似的
It's hot as hell in here.
空调肯定是坏掉了
AC must've shit the bed.
（系统故障）
抱歉这么热
Sorry for the heat.
该死的数字控制系统
Goddamn digital systems.
搞技术的人都不可信 我最清楚了
Never trust a guy in tech. Jesus, I should know that.
这堆东西都是什么
So what is all this stuff?
真实犯罪物品
Authentic criminological artifacts.
如果它做了什么坏事 八成就会收进这里
If it did something bad, chances are it's in here.
好好看 仔细看 看什么能把你吓一跳
Take a look around, take your time, see what pops out at you.
你有兴趣的 我都能给你详细讲讲
Anything piques your interest, I can tell you all about it.
每个物件背后都有悲伤又变态的故事
There's a sad, sick story behind most everything here.
正如我们的主展品 就在那边
Just like our main attraction just through there.
不过一步一步按顺序看
But let's not get ahead of ourselves.
好多人急着直接去参观帘子后面
A lot of folks just rush behind the curtain,
其余的连看都不怎么看
hardly even eyeball this stuff,
然后「大众放屁」之类的应用上
and then it's a bunch of one-star.
就会给你来一堆一星差评
ratings on Trip-fucker and before you know it…
听着 我一点都不急 所以你别担心
Yo, look, I am not in a rush, so don't worry.
那你慢慢看
Well, then, take your time.
我会的
I shall.
这些东西似乎挺高科技
This stuff looks techie.
我的学术背景是神经科技
Well, neuro tech was my background.
厉害
Sweet.
那这个是什么 看起来像个做发型的
So, what's this, then? Looks like a hairdressing thing.
其实这是我最早的一批藏品之一
Actually, that was one of my very first souvenirs.
能让你明白主展品是怎么来的
Sheds a little light on how our main exhibit came to be.
- 这是什么 - 你听说过彼得·道森吗
- What is it? - You heard of Peter Dawson?
彼得·道森医生
Dr. Peter Dawson?
我一般会介绍说这是道森联感诊断器
Well, usually I say this is Dawson's Symphatic Diagnoser,
然后观众大惊「不可能」 然后我说「就是」
and folks shriek, "No way, " and I'm like, "Oh, it very much is."
下一个问题一般是「你是怎么搞到的」
"How the heck did you get that?" is the next question.
- 好吧 - 我主攻医疗科技
- OK. - My domain was med tech.
我曾在圣朱尼佩医院工作
I worked out of St. Juniper's.
有点像大学医院
It's kind of like a university hospital.
地段特好 《土地法案》的一部分
Sweet setup. Part of the Land Act, actually.
就在纽约市区 挺老的一栋大楼
It was in downtown New York, big old building.
研究所在高层
Research up top,
急诊室和平头百姓去的地方则在沿街的低层
emergency room and the great unwashed down at street level.
那里完美结合了生意和医疗
It was the perfect mix of business and health care.
- 不是吧你 - 别挡路 傻逼
- Seriously? - Out of the way, asshole!
经营理念是给没医保的人免费投保
Idea was folks with no coverage signed up for free health care.
作为交换 他们要同意偶尔参加实验性治疗
in exchange for consenting to occasional experimental treatments.
我给高层的人干活儿
I… I… I worked for the guys up top.
就像个科学家吗
What, like a scientist?
我更像是个 招人的
I was more sort of… recruitment.
- 我来了 - 离手
- Yeah, yeah, I'm here. - Clear.
放电
Shocking.
- 没反应 - 没有吗
- No. - No?
- 没有 - 那我再来 离手 离手
- No. - OK, I'm going again. Clear. Clear!
放电
Shocking.
还是没有
No.
早知道她服了三环素 我会加大剂量的
If I'd known she was on tricyclics, I would have nudged the dose.
这无法预料
You couldn't have known.
不太是时候吗
This a bad time?
10层的罗洛·海恩斯
Rolo Haynes from the tenth floor.
你好像遇到麻烦了
Seems you've been having some problems.
我这里可能有帮得上你的东西
I think I got something that can help.
他们最感兴趣的就是神经技术
The big thing they're into is neuro technics.
开创性的大脑增强
Pioneering brain enhancements.
神经系统联接
Neural interfaces.
这些有意思的东西
All that fun stuff.
他们的终极目标
The holy grail they've been aiming for.
就是找到传输知识的方法
is a way to transfer knowledge.
其中一个小组在做一个实验
So one of the teams here is working on an experiment,
想找到办法
trying to find a way to.
将信息从一个大脑发射到另一个大脑
beam information from one brain to another.
这是肯尼
This is Kenny.
这是赫克托
This is Hector.
继续听我说
Stay with me on this.
我说说这个实验
So, the experiment.
他们造了一个小迷宫 然后把肯尼放了进去
They built a little maze and they drop Kenny here into it.
它在里面转来转去转了几个月
and he runs round over and over for months on end.
直到它对那里了如指掌
till he knows it like a childhood home.
然后 他们把这个戴在它身上
And then… they put this on him.
这是个发射器
It's a transmitter,
从肯尼的大脑中提取信号
absorbing signals from Kenny's brain.
传给那边的赫克托
which were sent to Hector over here.
赫克托佩戴着我们的原型突触接收器
Hector had our prototype synaptic receiver fitted.
记住 赫克托从未踏足过这个迷宫
Now, remember, Hector had never even set paw in the maze.
计划就是它现在会接收肯尼对迷宫布局的认知
Plan was he'd now receive Kenny's knowledge of the maze layout.
第一次进来的时候 就瞬间破解迷宫
and, boom, he'd be able to solve it, first time.
- 它成功了吗 - 没有
- And did he? - No.
像只老鼠一样乱窜 蠢透了
Scrabbled around like a rat, fucking imbecile.
那你跟我讲这个干什么
So, um, why are you telling me this?
因为正当迷宫实验宣告失败时
Because just as it becomes clear that the maze thing's a bust,
我们一位研究员把咖啡泼在肯尼身上了
one of our researchers spills his coffee on Kenny.
滚烫的咖啡泼了肯尼一身
Hot coffee spills all over Kenny,
它当然就大声惨叫
so obviously he's squealing like hell,
但赫克托也是如此
but so is Hector.
结果发现 我们没有发现如何分享知识
Turns out, we haven't discovered how to share knowledge…
- 但发现了如何分享生理感觉 - 答对了
- But physical sensations. - Bingo.
不可思议 天呐
That's nuts. Holy shit.
更不可思议的是
And even nutsier shit,
赫克托有烫伤感 但并没有任何损伤
Hector felt the burn, but took no damage at all.
感觉一模一样 但生理上却毫发无伤
All of the experience, none of the physical cost.
那它是怎么死的
But how did he die?
之后他们把它解剖了检查它身体是否有异样
They cut him open after to see if he was OK.
不管怎样 多亏了赫克托的牺牲
Anyhow, thanks to Hector's sacrifice,
我们做出了这个原型机
we prototyped this.
人类感受接收器
A receiver for human experiences.
神经系统植入物 只有这么一个
A neural implant. Only one of its kind.
这就是你带我来这里的原因
This is why you brought me up here.
诊治病人最烦人的事是什么
What's the biggest pain in the ass with patients?
很难查明他们的病症
Finding out what's wrong with them in the first place.
半数来这儿的混蛋们
Half of the assholes that roll in here.
连自己的症状都说不清楚
can't even describe their symptoms.
他们要么是失去了知觉 或是得了脑震荡
They're… They're out cold or concussed.
或是醉酒 太蠢
or drunk or dumb.
只有两岁 不会说英语
or… two years old, or they can't speak English.
想象一下 如果你能原样感受到病人的感觉
Imagine if you could feel exactly what a patient feels,
而不会有生理症状
minus the physical consequences.
就像读取他们的思想
Like reading their minds.
你觉得怎么样
So what do you say?
真得佩服道森 他立刻抓住了机会
Gotta hand it to Dawson, he lept at the chance.
他很乐意这样做
Like, he was happy to do it.
而且手术过程很短
And it was only a short procedure.
是不可逆的 但 他可是个先锋
Irreversible, but, hey, he was a pioneer.
再说 他的病人死亡率高得离奇
Plus, his mortality rates were in the toilet,
这是他赎罪的最好机会
so this was his best shot at redemption.
如果我碰它会疼吗
Does it hurt if I touch it?
应该不疼
I don't think so.
看起来有点重口
There's something kinda kinky about it.
就像终极穿环
It's like the ultimate piercing.
如果你是在安慰我 你成功了
If you're trying to make me feel better, it's working.
该试验运行了
Time for the trial run.
这时我们的发网装置就该登场了
So this is where our hairnet doohickey comes into play.
理论上讲 如果你把它戴在自愿对象上
Theory was, if you slipped it on a willing subject,
它就会提取他们的生理感觉
it'd absorb their physical sensations.
将其传送至道森的植入器上
and relay them to Dawson's implant.
我们只需判断它是否起效
We just had to find out if it worked.
这根手指
This one.
休斯顿 我们创造奇迹了
Houston, we got a miracle.
道森立刻开始诊治病患
Right off the bat, dawson gets to work with the ailing public,
开始建立生理症状的心理库
starts building up a kind of mental library of physical symptoms.
计划是 他能了解病症的感觉
Plan was, he'd get to know how things felt.
然后更快地做出诊断
so that he could diagnose them quicker.
先从急诊室的小病开始 轻微骨折之类
So, starts small in the ER, minor fractures, that sort of thing.
熟练后开始着手更重的病症
Soon graduates to bigger stuff.
严重受伤 各种疾病
Major injuries. Diseases.
晚期患者等
Late-stage terminal stuff.
道森咬牙坚持了下来
Dawson grit his teeth and went through it all.
比如说 一个小孩痛苦不堪
Say a kid comes in obviously in pain.
医生怀疑是阑尾炎
Doctors suspect appendicitis,
他们联系道森让他来确诊
they'd hook him up to Dawson just to be sure.
道森到这时已多次感受过阑尾炎
Dawson had felt appendicitis many times by now,
所以如果还有别的情况他会知道
so he knows if it's something more.
他发现了他们根本没想到隐疾
Caught things they weren't even looking for.
胚细胞瘤等
Blastomas and so on.
祝你好运
Good luck, man.
他救人无数 毫无疑问
That man saved lives, no doubt about it.
- 祝你们好运 - 再见
- Good luck, huh? - Bye.
- 保持联系 再见 - 再见
- Stay in touch. Bye-bye. - Bye.
太棒了
That was nice.
没想到的是
And, incidentally,
请原谅我如此粗鄙
if you'll allow me to be crude,
道森联感诊断器在床上很有用
Dawson's symphatic diagnoser came in handy in the bedroom.
他的植入物也能接收愉悦的感觉
His implant received pleasurable sensations, too.
如果他女朋友戴上蓝色传送头套
So if his girlfriend slipped on that transmitting blue hairnet.
他调好他的小接收植入物
and he tuned in his little implant nubbin…
就不仅能感受到他的感受
he didn't just feel what he was feeling…
- 我要高潮了 - 还能感受到她的感受
- I'm gonna come! - …but also felt what she was feeling.
这混蛋同时
Son of a bitch was experiencing.
体验了男性和女性的高潮
male and female orgasms at the same time.
- 天啊 - 天啊 天啊 天啊
- Oh, my… - Oh, my… Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
天啊
Oh, shit.
你真是让我停不下…
I can't get enough of your…
但是
But?
- 什么 - 道森过得很开心
- I'm sorry? - Dawson's having a great time.
肯定会有个「但是」
There's gotta be a "But."
他过得很开心 但是…
He's having a great time, but…
但是
But…
让一让 让一让
Coming through. Coming through.
- 快 - 快到了
- Come on. - Almost there.
有一天 惠特利参议员被紧急送来医院
One day, they rush in Senator Whitley.
他在一个慈善晚会上晕倒了
He'd collapsed at some fundraiser.
没人查得出来他怎么了
No one could tell what in hell was wrong with him.
- 抬 - 交给我
- Lift. - I got this.
道森接手了
Dawson's hooked up.
- 小心点 - 好
- Be careful. - OK.
- 天呐 - 这让他极其痛苦
- Jeez. - And has the roughest ride.
- 彼得 - 他好像完全不知道是怎么回事
- Pete? - Like he's got no clue what this is.
- 彼得 - 再给我一分钟 拜托
- Pete? - Just one more minute, please.
让他来
Let the man work.
这是一种他从未体验过的痛苦
It's a pain he's never known.
- 彼得 他没心跳了 - 再给我一分钟
- Pete, he's flatlining. - Just one more moment.
然后就那样发生了
And then it happened.
彼得
Pete?
道森昏迷了大概五分钟
Dawson blacked out, for, like, five minutes.
那个参议员是被人下毒了
Turns out the senator had been poisoned,
一种罕见的俄罗斯毒药
a rare poison at that, some kind of Russian shit.
是他自己造的孽
He'd been into that whole thing.
但是道森体验了死亡 并回到了人世
But Dawson had experienced death and come out the other side.
死亡来临的一刻
At the moment of death,
大量突触感应瞬间消失
a whole galaxy of synapses fritzes out of existence.
内啡肽排山倒海
Tsunami of endorphins.
然后紧接着涌来一阵虚无的暗潮
And then there's this rolling dark wave of nothing rushes in behind.
等他醒过来 他们对他做了各种检查
When he came round, they ran every kind of test.
他的系统一切正常
and he was all systems go, nothing wrong.
报告上写的是 「受惊 但未受伤」
"Shaken but unharmed, " They put on his report.
第二天 他又继续开工了
Next day, he was back up and at 'em.
但有些不对劲 是吗
But there was something wrong, right?
鬼门关走一遭回来
To go through all that without dying?
搞坏了他的植入物
Fucked up his implant like that.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
- 我去拿点水 - 好
- I'm just gonna get some water. - OK.
该死
Oh, goddamn it.
可以说他和痛苦的关系有所变化
Fair to say his relationship with pain had shifted a little.
疼死了
That hurt like hell.
现在他喜欢上它了
Now, he was into it.
那之后 他把精力全都投入到了工作上
He really threw himself into his work after that.
他一开始想隐瞒 但是由于那个小接收器
He tried to hide it at first, but thanks to that little nubbin,
他越是痛苦 就越是愉悦
the more pain he felt, the more pleasure he got.
不 停下
OK, no. Stop, stop.
停下 安全词 停下
Stop. OK, safe word. Stop!
- 你说了我们可以试试 - 我们试了
- You said that we could try it. - And we did.
我们试了拉头发和口球
Look, we tried the hair pulling and that choke thing.
我不喜欢 这不适合我
I'm not into it, OK? It's just not me.
也许我该走了
Maybe I should go.
不 不 不要
No. No, please.
对不起
I'm sorry.
留下来 好吗
Stay. Please?
彼得
Pete!
我要走了
I'm going.
你看 就像吃辣椒
See, it's like eating chilies.
你会适应得很快
You acclimatize fast.
你第一次吃墨西哥辣椒肯定马上吐掉 太辣了
First time you had a jalapeno, bet you spat it out, too hot.
但坚持下来就会上瘾
But persevere and it becomes addictive.
很快 一个墨西哥辣椒已经不够了
Soon, a jalapeno's not enough.
你追求越来越高 红辣椒 鸟眼辣椒
You work your way up, red-hot chilies, bird's-eye chilies,
一直到苏格兰魔鬼椒
till you get to them Scotch bonnet devils.
道森的渴望也是一样
Dawson's craving was just the same.
不知不觉 他开始经常去急诊室
Before you know it, he's hanging around the ER.
想等下一个事故受害者再给他这种体验
just waiting for a juicy accident victim to latch onto.
他满脑子只有对下一次痛感的期待
All he can think about is that next hit gnawing away up there.
「再给我 再给我 再给我」
"Give it back to me. Give it back. I gotta have it back."
莎拉 你能帮我提交这些吗
Sarah, will you just, um, file these for me?
- 好的 - 彼得
- Sure thing. - Pete.
- 现在不是你当班 - 带他去四号床
- This isn't your shift. - Take him round to bay four.
- 好 - 我只是…
- OK. - I just…
彼得
Pete.
小心
Careful.
三 二 一
And three, two, one.
抬
Lift.
交给我吧
Let me get this.
他一戴上 就感觉到了
Soon as he jacks in, he feels it.
是心脏病 她在街上晕倒了
It's a cardiac arrest. She collapsed in the street.
我只是想确定一下
I just wanna be sure.
的确是心脏病 但他什么都没说
It's a heart attack all right, but he says nothing.
慢慢享受
Plays for time.
以为他能乘着痛苦
Figures he can ride that pain train.
享受极乐
all the way through to nirvana.
最后他们只能强行把道森从她身边拉开
Eventually they have to physically pull Dawson away from her.
给艾瑟尔婆婆做心肺复苏
Give Aunt Ethel her CPR.
她在他面前死去 他却像个酒鬼
She flatlines in front of him, and he's like an alcoholic.
看着一杯上好的威士忌被倒进水池里
watching someone pour a glass of good Scotch down the sink,
因好东西被浪费而难过
sick at the waste of good shit.
我们一直都清楚 这可能会有副作用
Look, we always knew going into this there might be side effects.
我们可以研究一下如何停止
I mean, we can look into how we deactivate,
但需要时间
but it's gonna take some time.
我不能从其他项目撤人出来 彼得
I can't just pull all the people off the other projects, Pete.
我们还有目标要实现 这你懂的
I mean, we have milestones to hit. You know the drill.
但我们会成功的
But we'll get there.
在此期间 我们不能让你靠近病人
In the meantime, we can't have you near patients,
回家吧
so just go home,
休息一下 连刷一整部迷你剧什么的
put your feet up and binge a miniseries, whatever.
没人能料到接下来会发生什么
No one could have known what'd happen next.
有关部门将确认
Authorities are expected to confirm.
尸体是失踪的WNL天气预报员丹妮斯·斯托克利
the body is that of missing WNL weather reporter Denise Stockley.
我们可以看见 大量警力聚集在那里
Certainly a major police presence there, as we can see.
我们来看看时间线
Let's take a look at the timeline…
道森整天都独自在家
Dawson was home alone 24/7,
烦躁不安 大概是戒断反应
climbing the walls. Withdrawal, I guess.
人们最后一次见到她是9月15日周五晚上
She was last seen the evening of Friday, September 15th…
不再有病人供他榨取痛苦
He didn't have patients to leech pain off anymore.
所以他开始给自己施加痛苦
So he started inflicting it… on himself.
如果能让她安全归来
For her safe return,
或者是有目击者提供任何相关信息
or for any information from witnesses…
整整一周他都在自残
Spent a week just whittling away at himself.
这里切切 那里凿凿
Cut here, a gouge there.
他毕竟是医生
I mean, the guy was a doctor.
他知道最多可以切到什么程度而不会丧命
He knew how far he could go without it getting fatal.
但永远不够
But it was never enough.
无论怎么做都不够
None of it was enough.
他自残的时候
When he worked on himself,
少了一样至关重要的因素
there was a crucial ingredient missing.
恐惧
Fear.
杏仁核
The amygdala.
脑中杏仁状的小核
Little almond-shaped nubbin in your brain.
你害怕的时候 它会活跃起来
When you're afraid, it lights up.
就像午夜空袭 让感觉变灵敏
like a midnight airstrike, sharpens the senses.
病人盯着顶灯
The fear the patient feels.
所感觉到的恐惧
when they're staring up at that ceiling light,
伴随冷不丁刺一下的痛苦而来的恐惧
the fear accompanying each sudden jab of agony,
他渐渐也喜欢上了那个
he'd come to appreciate that, too.
它和痛苦如影随形
It went with the pain.
是痛苦的补充 就像红酒和牛排
Complemented it, like red wine and steak.
你可以给自己施加痛苦 但恐惧没法只靠自己
You can inflict pain on yourself, but not terror.
要想得到恐惧 需要一个志愿者
For that, you need a volunteer.
人们找到道森的时候 他正在高潮
Dawson was practically coming when they found him.
享受着恐惧 痛苦和死亡的混合毒品
He'd enjoyed one big old speedball of fear and pain and death.
他们把他关进监狱了吧
Tell me they put him in jail.
送进了医院
In the hospital.
他成了植物人
He wound up in a vegetative state.
那就好
Good.
直到今天还在
Still there to this day.
陷入了深海一般的昏迷中
In a coma, deep as the ocean.
但是
But the thing of it is,
人们说 他脸上还是那个表情
they say he still has that look on his face.
幸福满溢
Blissed out.
依然沉醉在高潮里
Still riding that high.
你在逗我吧
You're fucking with me, right?
好吧 擎天柱是我编的 忍不住
OK, I added the boner. I couldn't resist.
- 很有意思吧 - 是有意思
- Fun story, huh? - Yep, fun story.
天啊
Oh, man.
想喝水吗
Do you want some water?
- 不用了 - 没关系的
- Really, I'm fine. - No, man, it's no bother.
十分感谢
Thank you kindly.
你怎么没继续干医疗科技
So, how come you didn't stay in med tech?
我又干了一段时间
Well, I did for a while.
不能因为道森成了植物人 就停止神经研究
Just 'cause Dawson went la-la, neuro research didn't stop.
TCKR对它进行了改进和微调
TCKR adapted it and fine-tuned it.
数码意识传输
It's how they wound up.
就是这样创造出来的
with the digital consciousness transference,
现在叫意识存储器了
what they call cookies today.
就像他们把老人上传到云端
Uh, like when they upload old people to the cloud?
对 但这比那项技术早多了
Yeah, but this was way before that.
当时没有完备的浸入式虚拟现实环境
We didn't have that whole immersive VR environment shizzle back then.
我们更多是在生物层面上的 低保真
What we dealt with was more organic, almost lo-fi.
怎么说
How so?
你问的问题比普通人多
Gotta say you ask more questions than the average bear.
说实话 我的车还在充电
Well, to be honest, my car's still charging,
所以我有时间
so I've got a bit of time.
那么 我想给你展示
Well, then, what I wanted to show you, um…
我当时研究的一部分
Part of what I was working on…
还挺…可爱
It's, um… cute?
其实是本馆最悲哀的东西之一
Actually, one of the saddest things in the whole place.
看着可不像
Doesn't look it.
你有没有经历过这样一段感情
You ever had one of those relationships.
你完全没法把那人从脑海里赶走
where you just can't get someone out of your head?
- 有过 - 数年前 男孩遇见了女孩
- Yeah. - Some years back, boy meets girl.
男孩叫杰克 女孩叫…
Boy's called Jack, girl's called…
- 吉尔 - 凯莉
- Jill. - Carrie.
吃纸杯蛋糕吗
Cupcake?
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 你现在是警长了 - 对
- Are you the sheriff now? - Yeah.
- 我是囚犯 - 你有麻烦了 先生
- And I'm the prisoner? - You're in trouble, sir.
来抓我啊
Come and arrest me.
最后 他的屌往她的屁股里吐了黏糊糊的种子
Eventually, he dick-pukes a little baby paste up her wazoo,
种子生根了
which takes hold.
还没回过神 就冒出一个男孩
Before you know it, out pops a boy.
帕克
Parker.
就这样 他们组成了一个家庭
Boom. They're a family unit.
幸福美满 其乐融融
A walking commercial for a sunnier future. Happy as hell.
我想给你们拍张照片
I wanna… I wanna take a photo.
我要把背景的湖也拍进去
OK. I'm gonna get the lake in the background.
- 来 伙计 - 准备好了吗
- All right, buddy. - OK, you ready?
帕克
Parker.
和妈妈招手 和妈妈打个招呼
Wave to Mommy. Say hello. Say hi to Mommy.
凯莉被卡车撞了
Carrie gets hit by a truck.
躺在了圣朱尼佩医院
Winds up at St. Juniper's.
回到我身边吧
Come back to me.
醒来吧
Come back.
几年过去了
Years go by.
杰克每周都来看她 和她说话
Jack visits her every week, talks to her,
放他们儿子的录音 东扯西扯
plays her recordings of their son, shoots the shit.
她一直没醒
She never wakes up.
但他们给她装了台通讯盒子做测试
But they tested the comm box on her.
一种帮助昏迷病人做出简单回应的基础装置
A kind of basic device that let coma folks sort of respond back.
我带了些清新剂 你想要松林味的吗
I got you some room fresheners. You want pine forest?
那好
Ok.
柑橘味呢
What about citrus fresh?
好嘞
Gotcha.
我还录了帕克和别的孩子一起唱的歌
And I recorded Parker singing with some other kids.
你想听吗
You wanna hear it?
*一闪一闪亮晶晶*
*Twinkle, twinkle, little star*
*满天都是小星星*
*How I wonder what you are*
302房的女人 凯莉·拉曼斯
The woman in 302, Carrie Lamasse.
你是她的伴侣 对吗
You're the partner, right?
杰克
Jack?
我是罗洛·海恩斯 TCKR神经研发部代表
Rolo Haynes. I represent neuro R&D for TCKR.
好的
Ok.
我们正在研究一个项目
We're working on a project that.
也许会对你这种情况的人有所帮助
might be of interest to someone in your position.
我什么情况
What's… What's my position?
我们正探索的项目 可以给凯莉这样的人
We're exploring something that could give the likes of Carrie.
带来新生
a whole new lease of life.
我说的是奇迹
I'm talking miraculous.
什么意思
What do you mean?
TCKR的人一直在研究
So the guys at TCKR have been working.
将一个大脑里的意识数字化地抽取出来
on digitally extracting a consciousness out of one brain.
再安置到宿主大脑中去
and kind of rehousing it in a host brain.
- 这是什么意思 - 好吧
- What does that even mean? - OK.
我们平时最多只会用大脑容量的40%
So, even on a good day, we only use 40% of our brain capacity.
剩下60%的大脑
There is this whole other 60% of our noggin.
就像空房间一样 没有利用起来
hanging around like an empty Airbnb.
所以
And so…?
所以有了我们的「压缩」技术
And so with our new compression technique,
我们就可以将另一个意识
we figure we can fit another whole consciousness.
移植到大脑没利用到的空间里
into that unused space.
我的意思就是
I'm talking about taking.
把凯莉的意识从那具破损的躯壳取出
Carrie's consciousness from that broken shell.
放到那里
and putting it in there.
什么 她的声音会在我脑子里
What? Um… Like a voice inside my head?
她整个人都在你脑子里
Like the whole of her inside your head.
类似她成了乘客 搭了你的车
Like a hitchhiker. Like a passenger.
她会有间接感知 她能看到你所看到的
Vicarious sensations. She sees what you see.
感受你所感受的
She feels what you feel.
她可以获得新生
She can live again.
- 「感受」… - 你们有个儿子 帕克
- "Feels" as in…? - You got a little boy. Parker.
你怎么知道
How do you know all this?
你拥抱帕克 凯莉也会感觉到
You hug Parker and Carrie feels it too.
她可以通过你拥抱你们的儿子
She can hug your son via you.
这要花多少钱
How much does this all cost?
一分钱也不用
Won't cost a thing.
在移植过程中
We will have to euthanize.
我们必须将她的躯体安乐死
her physical body during the transfer process,
但我们会保留她的器官用于捐献移植
but we would earmark her organs for transplants.
为社会做些贡献
Giving back to the community.
你意下如何
So what do you say?
我得考虑一下
I'd have to think about it.
凯莉已经想好了
Carrie's done her thinking.
你呢
How about you?
开始「上传」程序
Commencing upload procedure.
开始「下载」
Now moving to download.
好 她「安装」好了
OK, she's installed.
她到家了
She's home.
你可以睁开眼睛了 杰克
You can open your eyes now, Jack.
凯莉
Carrie?
你能听到的话 告诉杰克你看到了什么
If you can hear me, tell Jack what you see.
一个苹果 我看到一个苹果
An… An apple. I… I see an apple.
我能听见她说话
I can hear her.
苹果 苹果 她说看到了苹果
Apple. Apple. She's saying apple.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
杰克
Hey, Jack.
拿着
Take it.
握住它
Grip it.
凯莉 能感觉到吗
Carrie, you feel that?
她说能感觉到
She says she feels it.
感官正常 咬一口
Sensations looking good. Take a bite.
天呐
Oh, God.
我好久没尝到食物的味道了
So long since I tasted anything.
你能尝到吗
You can taste that?
她尝到了 我的天
She tastes it. Holy shit.
看来一切顺利
Looks like you're all set.
- 可以把他带进来了 - 来吧 宝贝
- Shall we bring him in? - Come on in, honey.
是帕克吗
Is that Parker?
他长这么大了
He got so big.
杰克 抱住他 抱抱我们的儿子
Oh, God, Jack, hold him. Hold our little boy.
给我个大大的拥抱
Give me a really big hug, please.
我能感觉到 我能感觉到他
I feel him. I really feel him.
妈咪说她爱你
Mommy says she loves you.
真的很暖心
Truly heartwarming.
没错 但总是有个「但是」
Yeah. But this is where you say "But."
虽然不想深挖哲学 但是
Well, not to wax philosophical, but…
幸福感到底可以持续多久呢
how long can happiness realistically last anyhow?
（一千五百万的价值）
快翻页啊
Turn the page already.
你阅读速度真慢
Man, you read slow.
我喜欢细细品味图片
I like to take in the pictures.
这是绘本的绘画部分所在
That's what the graphic part of a graphic novel is.
没错
It's true.
我得去趟厕所
I gotta take a piss.
我永远不会习惯这个的
I'll never get used to this.
是不是感觉很棒
Feels good, huh?
你不给我们洗手吗
You're not washing our hands?
我们的手
Our hands?
说真的 有点恶心
Seriously, though, it's kind of gross.
今天 38岁的克莱顿·雷因残忍杀害了
38-year-old Clayton Leigh was today found guilty.
WNL天气预报员丹妮斯·斯托克利被定罪
of the horrific murder of WNL weather reporter Denise Stockley,
她的残尸在一年前的今天被发现
whose mutilated remains were discovered one year ago today.
我们该关掉这个 对4岁孩子来说太血腥了
We should turn this off. It's disturbing to a four-year-old.
没事 他都没在听
He's fine. He's not even listening.
帕克 老天
Parker! Jesus.
- 别对他发火 - 冲我发火就可以吗
- Don't snap at him. - But snapping at me is fine?
- 亲爱的 - 这样如何
- Baby, you're… - How does that work?
他是个孩子
He's a child.
这很严重 怎么
This is serious, man. Wha…
不 不 我没有 我没有不讲理
No, no, I'm not being… I'm not being unreasonable.
不 等等 不 听我说
No, just wait. No. Just… Just hear me out.
有一个永远不离开的后座司机
Having a back-seat driver glued into the back seat.
对车里的人来说可不怎么好受
ain't no fun for anyone in the car.
他没有隐私 她无法行动
No privacy for him. No agency for her.
- 这会让你发疯的 - 没错
- It'd drive you mental. - Exactly.
好吧 当我没说
You know, fine, forget it.
好 继续 继续说
All right, go ahead. Keep talking.
我要吃凤尾鱼了
I'm going for the anchovies.
你能保持安静吗
You gonna be quiet?
你现在想闭嘴了吗 行吗
You wanna shut up now? You're good?
你
You…
去你的
Fuck you.
妈的
Fuck.
对 我不在乎
Yeah. I don't… I don't care.
你还在说话
You… you're still talking.
你
You…
总之
Anyhow,
他或他们不久后就来找我了
soon he or they come to me.
就像我是他们的情感治疗师
Like I'm their relationship therapist.
你能消停一下让我说吗
Would you pipe down and let me speak?
让我起码说完一句话
Let me finish a goddamn sentence.
我知道问题所在了
Guys, I see the problem.
她才是问题所在
She's the problem.
亲不敬 熟生蔑就是问题
Familiarity breeding contempt is the problem.
你们需要限制联系
You need to ration your contact.
怎么限制
Ration how?
她在我的脑子里就像一支忘不掉的曲子
She's running through my head like a goddamn tune I can't shake.
我们可以升级你的权限 杰克
Well, we could upgrade your privileges, Jack.
给你更多控制权
Give you a little more control.
闭嘴 抱歉 继续说
Shut up! Sorry. Go on.
如果你有能力
Well, maybe if you had the ability.
时不时暂停凯莉的感知
to place Carrie on pause now and then…
对你们俩来说都会好些
it'd make things easier for the both of you.
就这么办
Do it.
我才不管呢 就这么办
Whatever. Whatever. Whatever. Do it.
所以他升级了他的权限
So he upped his privileges.
- 现在可以暂停她了 - 这个吗
- Should be able to put her on pause. - This one?
- 没错 - 好的
- That's it. - OK.
他没过多久就开始使用
Didn't take him long to use 'em.
所以我们现在堂而皇之地看辣妹吗
So now we're just openly checking out women's racks?
别说你没有
And don't say you weren't.
因为我能感觉你硬了
because I can feel the fucking boner forming, OK?
在她离开时还盯着人家的屁股 妈的
And he checks her ass too as she leaves. Holy fuck.
我就打量她了 怎么着
So I checked her out. What?
我都憋死了 已经快一个月没撸过一发了
I'm horny as fuck, haven't jerked off in, like, a month.
我可没阻止你啊
Well, I'm not stopping you.
你在我脑袋里一直盯着我
You're looking over my shoulder but from the inside.
就像是在一个警察面前撸
It's like trying to jerk off in front of a cop.
这警察还是你妈
who's also your mom.
- 去你的 - 好吧 告诉你
- Fuck you! - OK, you know what?
够了 我受够了
That's it. That's it. That's it.
够了 我要暂停你
Time out. I'm putting you on pause.
不 杰克 你敢
No. Jack, don't you dare.
杰克 杰克 我警告你
Jack. Jack, I'm warning you.
这太过分了
Not cool.
别再这样了
Don't do that again.
我们到家了吗
Are… Are we at home?
为什么有万圣节南瓜
Why the Halloween pumpkin?
万圣节离现在还有几个月
Halloween's months from now.
其实 就是今天
Actually, it's today.
我被暂停了多久
How long was I on pause?
就几周
Just a few weeks.
我也不清楚 八周
I don't know. Eight?
我明白 我很抱歉
OK, I know. I'm… I'm sorry.
我知道 抱歉 我也过意不去
I know. I'm sorry. I felt really bad.
所以我给你买了这个
So, um, I got you this.
今天算是我们的纪念日 所以
Figured it's kind of our anniversary, so…
去你的 你个混蛋
Fuck you. You're a fucking asshole.
你要不要我吃这个纸杯蛋糕
You want me to eat this cupcake or not?
橙味奶油糖霜
Orange cream icing.
- 帕克在哪里 - 这可是你的最爱
- Where's Parker? - Your favorite.
我想见帕克
I wanna see Parker.
你让我几个月没见到他
You had him away from me for months.
我想见我的儿子
I wanna see my boy.
好的
Ok.
他在哪里
Where is he?
你在忙什么呢
What you got going on there?
- 那是辆消防车吗 - 是的
- Is that a fire truck? - Yeah.
告诉他我爱他
Tell him I love him.
哥们 妈妈爱你
Buddy, Mommy loves you.
什么
What?
告诉他我需要一个拥抱
Tell him I need a hug.
还有 知道吗
You wanna know something else?
妈妈想要抱抱
Mommy needs a hug.
天哪
God!
帕克让事情复杂了
Parker complicated things.
他们都觉得要为他负责
They both felt responsibility for him,
所以他们想要各退一步
so they tried to compromise,
达成共识 像大人那样
you know, reach an agreement, like adults.
在平时 杰克都把凯莉暂停 而到了周末
Jack put Carrie on pause except for the weekends,
他会带着凯莉跟帕克出去玩
when they'd take Parker out with Carrie in attendance,
有点像拥有探视权的离婚夫妻
kind of like a divorcee with visiting rights.
你去藏起来吧
You go hide.
就这样
That's it!
被你骗到了
You tricked me.
下来
Come down here.
我来了
I'm coming.
这个办法还行
It worked OK.
维持了一段时间
For a while.
看来我们是邻居
Looks like we're neighbors.
我刚搬进来
I've just moved in.
- 艾米丽 - 杰克 很高兴认识你
- Emily. - Jack. Nice to meet you.
拜托
Oh, please.
- 这是谁 - 他叫帕克
- Who's this? - It's Parker.
好酷的名字
Cool name.
回头见
Guess I'll see you around.
好
Yeah.
回头见
Guess I'll see you around.
她只是表示友好 好吗
She was nice, OK?
别狡辩了
Cut the shit.
我知道你都精虫上脑了 好吗
I know when your hormones are flowing, OK?
在我们讲话的同时 我们的蛋蛋都涨大了
Our balls are brewing up a blow load as we speak.
现在别闹 我们的儿子还在呢
I can't. I'm with our son.
我没泡过谁
I didn't hit on anyone.
你知道吗 算了 探视时间结束了
You know what? Fuck it. Visiting time is over.
不 杰克 你敢 杰克
No. Jack, don't you dare. Jack.
杰克 你这个婊子养…
Jack, you son of a bi…
帕克 等等
Parker, wait up.
不管怎样 渐渐地
Anyhow, as time passed by,
杰克跟邻居好上了
Jack got it on with the neighbor.
而凯莉对此并不开心
And Carrie didn't take it so good.
她平日都要工作 我们只是想一起过个周末
She works all week. We just wanted to spend a weekend together.
天哪 你就不能为我们感到高兴吗
Jesus, can't you just be happy for us?
不 杰克 很奇怪 我做不到
No, Jack, weirdly enough, I can't.
天哪 你真刻薄
Christ, you are so bitter.
不 为什么
No. Why?
她在为难你吗
Is she giving you shit?
凯莉 别为难他了
Carrie, stop giving him shit.
让她滚开
Tell her to back off.
- 我… - 告诉她
- I… - Tell her.
天哪
Jesus Christ.
所以周末的办法不管用了
So the weekend thing isn't working.
我们试过限制她到一小时
And we tried limiting her to an hour…
但你知道她就在那儿
But you can tell that she's in there,
不断地挑刺和说坏话
like that judging and bitching.
时间限制让凯莉很苦恼
The time frame is frustrating for Carrie.
凯莉让我们很苦恼
Carrie is frustrating for us.
你现在把凯莉暂停了吗
You got Carrie on pause now?
好吧 其实
OK, well…
你还是可以把她删除的
there's always deletion.
- 就是说… - 将她永久抹去
- As in…? - As in permanent erasure.
不
No.
那是杀死她
That'd… That'd be killing her.
在法律上不算
Not legally.
但道德上是
But ethically.
拜托 她只是你大脑中残存的代码
Please. She is just some leftover code in your head.
那就像删除一封邮件一样
It'll be like… like deleting an email.
不
No.
不 不能删除 我做不到
No. No deletion. I'm not doing it.
她想陪伴帕克
She wants to be near Parker.
我不能剥夺她的这个权利
I can't take that away from her.
你肯定还有办法的
There's gotta be something you can do.
我的朋友们
My friends…
你们运气不错
you're in luck.
我们正在对这个产品进行封闭测试
It's something we're beta testing.
目标用户其实是重病晚期的父母
It's actually aimed at terminally ill parents.
有点像给他们孩子的纪念品
Kind of like a souvenir for their kids.
这个
Here.
一只猴子
A monkey?
更像是一个留念
More like a keepsake.
我们可以把她放进去
We can put her in here.
放到那里
In there?
它有个意识接收器
It's… It has a consciousness receptor,
有点像我们放进你大脑里的那个
kind of like the one we put in your head,
不过它是个原型机
but a prototype.
这里有个摄像头 所以她能看见帕克
And there's a camera here so she can see Parker.
另外 整个身体具有触觉反馈
Plus the whole body's got haptic feedback,
所以如果小帕克给它一个拥抱 她会感觉到
so if little Parkie gives it a cuddle, she'll feel it.
而且她也能进行反馈
And she can communicate back,
但用一种小孩子喜欢的受限方式
but in a kid-friendly, controlled way.
我不知道 我得想想
Yeah, I don't know. I'm gonna have to think about it.
我说可以
I say yes.
她已经想好了 你呢
Well, she's done her thinking. How about you?
转移进行得很快
The transfer went pretty fast.
凯莉完全不知道这件事正在发生
Carrie wouldn't have even been aware it was happening.
直到她醒来
Till she woke up.
来吧 你得把它撕开 撕开包裹
Come on, buddy, you gotta tear it. Tear into that thing.
- 杰克 - 你差不多搞定了
- Jack? - You almost got it.
就是这样
There you go.
好 把它拿出来吧
All right, pull it out.
好了
There you go.
是什么 帕克
What is it, Parker?
小猴
Monkey.
什么
What?
是不是很棒
That's pretty cool, huh?
杰克 杰克 这怎么回事
Jack. Jack, what the fuck?
但你知道吗
But you know something?
这个 这个
This… This, uh…
这是只很特别的小猴
This is a very special monkey.
- 是妈妈给你的 - 什么
- Mom wanted you to have it. - What?
每次你拥抱它 妈妈就会知道
Every time you hug it, Mom will know,
她也能感觉到那个拥抱
and she'll feel that hug too.
不不 杰克 把我放回你的脑袋里去
No. No, no, Jack, Jack, put me back in your fucking head.
杰克
Jack!
这只小猴还可以和你说话
And this monkey can speak to you.
可以让你知道它的感受
It can let you know how it feels.
她怎么说话
How did she speak?
语音设置是比较原始的
Well, the comm setup was a little rudimentary.
这是个原型机嘛
I mean, this is a prototype.
杰克
Jack!
不
No.
小猴爱你
Monkey loves you.
那是什么
What was that?
小猴想要抱抱
Monkey needs a hug.
给小猴一个抱抱
Give monkey a hug.
小猴爱你
Monkey loves you.
小猴想要抱抱 小猴爱你 小猴爱你
Monkey needs a hug. Monkey loves you. Monkey loves you.
小猴爱你 小猴 小猴想要抱抱
Monkey loves you. Monkey… Monkey… Monkey needs a hug.
- 我觉得 - 小猴爱你
- Yeah, I think… - Monkey loves you.
小猴 小猴想要抱抱
Monkey… Monkey needs a hug.
小猴需要点时间
Monkey just needs a minute.
适应自己的新环境
to get used to how things are gonna be.
听着 你个臭婊子
Now, listen, you fucking bitch.
我们依然可以删除你
We can still have you wiped.
你是不是想这样
That what you want?
用「小猴想要抱抱」表示「不」
Do "Monkey needs a hug" for no.
小猴想要抱抱
Monkey needs a hug.
你能不能做个好玩具
Are you gonna be a good toy?
小猴爱你
Monkey loves you.
那最好
You better.
总之 最终
Anyhow, in the end,
帕克厌烦了他的新玩具
Parker got tired of his new toy.
孩子嘛
But that's kids.
他们不知感恩
They're ingrates.
小猴需要抱抱
Monkey needs a hug.
等等 这是个犯罪博物馆
Wait, so this is a crime museum.
这里的罪何在
Where's the crime in this?
小猴就是罪
Well, the monkey is the crime.
几年前
See, a couple of years back,
联合国认定将人类意识
the UN made it illegal.
上传到这样的有限制载体上是非法的
to transfer human consciousnesses into limited formats like this.
载体得至少能表现出
Gotta be able to express at least.
人类的五种情感 这样才人道
five emotions for it to be humane, apparently.
意识存储器也得讲人权 对吧 凯莉
Human rights for cookies. Right, Carrie?
小猴需要抱抱
Monkey needs a hug.
她还在里面吗
She's still in there?
删除她也是不合法的 所以 没错
It'd be illegal to delete her too, so, yeah.
就这样了
Go figure.
总之 美国公民自由联盟开始声讨
Anyhow, ACLU raised one heck of a stink,
感谢这只臭猴子
and so thanks to this son of a monkey,
我被踢出了TCKR
I was out on my ass from TCKR.
连遣散费都没有
Not even a severance package.
这就是我建立这个地方的原因
It's why I started this place.
总得另辟蹊径
Had to branch out somehow,
而且我猜它正符合我的趣味
and it appealed to the carny in me, I guess.
小猴需要抱抱
Monkey needs a hug.
空调还不好使 真热
Goddamn AC's still not working. it's hot.
但我已经让你等太久了
But I've kept you waiting too long.
你准备好看主展品了吗
You ready for the prime exhibit?
这边走
Step right this way.
听着 我得警告你
Listen, I gotta warn you,
他不是曾经的样子了
he's not the man he once… was.
- 抱歉 - 你还需要水吗
- Sorry. - Do you want some more water?
我没事
I'm fine.
他在这边
He's this way.
过来 你有个访客
Come on, mister! You got a visitor.
这位是克莱顿·雷
May I present Clayton Leigh,
天气预报员杀人犯
weather girl killer.
我知道 他现在都闷闷的
I know, he's kind of mopey these days.
看上去怪可怜的
Cuts kind of a pathetic figure.
但别太为他感到抱歉
But don't feel too sorry for him.
他是个被判有罪的杀人犯
He is a convicted murderer.
我们可别忘了丹妮斯·斯托克利
Lest we forget Denise Stockley.
可怜可爱的女孩
Tragic and cute.
是不是啊 克莱顿
Ain't that right, Clayton?
他其实在看你
He's actually looking at you.
小心 可能他喜欢你这型的
Look out. Maybe you're his type.
他看上去好真实
He looks so real.
这就是他 或者说是他完整的上传意识
Well, it is him, or a fully conscious upload of him.
你可能在想他是怎么进去的
You're probably wondering how he got in here.
TCKR把我开除后
After TCKR kicked me out,
我的计划原本是做名人意识这一块
my plan was to branch out into celebrity consciousnesses,
征求名人的同意
sign up famous people and.
让他们在死后能以全息影像的方式重生
reincarnate them as holograms after they die.
有点像活人版杜莎夫人蜡像馆
Kind of like a living Madame Tussauds.
但名人麻烦多
But celebrities, that's just a quagmire.
太多版权问题 混蛋代理人
Too many rights issues, asshole representatives.
但被判有罪的杀人犯呢
But convicted killers?
就是另一回事了
It's a different story.
雷先生 请允许我自我介绍一下
Mr. Leigh, allow me to introduce myself.
- 我叫罗洛·海恩斯 - 听说你是搞科技的
- My name is Rolo Haynes. - They say you're in technology.
- 没错 - 那你能帮我查查DNA的事吗
- Uh, yes, that is true. - So you can look into this DNA thing?
证明不是我
Prove it wasn't me?
嗯 这当然有可能
Um, yes, that's certainly a possibility,
但这不是我来的原因
but that's not why I'm here.
- 我有一个提议 - 再见
- I have a proposal. - Goodbye.
等等 我有一个提议 我能帮你
No, wait. I have a proposal. I can help.
我可以帮你的家人
I can help your family.
你怎么说服他的
How'd you talk him into it?
没怎么费力就说服了
He didn't need much convincing.
就是万一发生最坏的情况 将你的数字自我
So really it's just signing over the rights to your digital self.
转让给我
in case the worst happens,
我保证你的亲属
and I promise your relatives.
将会获得大笔利润
will receive the lion's share of any profits.
所以 如果 万一
So if, you know, God forbid,
你被送上电椅
you do get sent to the chair,
你知道你的家人将一辈子衣食无忧
you know your family will be provided for, for life.
- 他的家人觉得如何 - 他们完全不在乎
- How'd his family feel about it? - They didn't give a shit.
在他被抓后就不管他了
Abandoned him the moment he got locked up.
可不是啊
I know, right?
老天 克莱 这是你的灵魂
Jesus Christ, Clay, it's your soul.
才没有那种东西
Ain't no such thing.
这只是电脑模拟出来的什么东西
It's just a computer simulation or somethin'.
那他为什么需要你的许可
Then why does he need your permission?
如果我能获得特赦 那就无所谓了
If my pardon comes through, it won't matter.
如果没有呢
And if it doesn't?
如果他们让我上电椅 你们能得到钱
Then if they send me to the chair, this is gonna pay.
能让你和孩子们有钱生活
It's gonna keep you and the kids above water,
不会流落街头
maintain a roof over y'all.
亲爱的 别这样
Baby, don't.
这可能是件好事呢
This could be a good thing.
但他没有等来赦免
But he never did get that pardon.
当然不会 因为他有罪嘛
Shit, no, 'cause he was guilty.
但不是有些疑点吗 你知道那个纪录片吧
But wasn't there some doubt? You know, that documentary?
假新闻 都是诽谤
Fake news. Hatchet job.
- 那篡改DNA呢 - 你不是认真的吧
- What about the DNA tampering? - Seriously?
那件案子没有任何疑点
There's no doubt about it.
他上电椅的那天
The day he got the chair.
是正义胜利的日子
was a great day for justice.
克莱顿无法抱怨
Clayton couldn't complain.
他可是会成为一个先驱
I mean, he was gonna be a pioneer.
我要抽取他全部的意识
I was gonna slurp up his entire consciousness.
他将是第一个从死刑中存活的人
He'd be the first guy on death row to survive his own execution.
转移进行得很顺利
The transfer went beautifully.
很快 克莱顿就重生了
Before I knew it, Clayton was born again.
你好 哥们
Hi, buddy.
祝贺你
Congratulations to you.
你可以说已经进入来世了
You're in the afterlife, so to speak.
看上去不错
Looking good.
我是个幽灵吗
Am I a ghost?
如果你觉得是就是吧
If that helps, yeah.
我只需要进行一些测试 好吗
I just gotta test a few things here, OK?
这看上去可能有点怪 在那里先别动
So this may seem a little weird. Just hang on in there.
（对象已就绪）
这是怎么回事
What the fuck?
我知道光是看那家伙困在里面团团转
See, I knew just seeing the guy walking around captive,
已经不错了 但还不够吸引眼球
that was good, but that wasn't much of a draw.
但亲自拉操纵杆呢
But pulling the lever yourself?
就称得上是景点了
Now, that's an attraction.
好了
OK.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
道森的疼痛技术为这个铺了路
Dawson's pain tech had paved the way for it.
完美重现了
A perfect re-creation.
电刑的痛苦感觉
of exactly how the agony of electrocution feels.
每一伏都完全仿真
Every volt simulated for real.
关键是不能让他在最大电压中超过15秒
Key was, never let him exceed 15 seconds at max voltage.
这会永远删除他的数字突触 杀了他
That would wipe his digital synapses out for good, kill him.
10秒看上去是最佳电击时长
Ten seconds seemed to be the optimum shock length,
因此成了没法解除的限制
so that became the intractable limit.
好了 休息一下
OK. Have a little rest.
适应一下你的新房间
Get used to your room.
明天就正式开馆了
Official opening's tomorrow.
其实早期时候 接待所有访客才是个问题
In fact, in the early days, the problem was fitting everyone in.
求你别这样做
Please don't do it.
求你 求你 求你
Please, please, please, please, please. Please.
求你了 别
Please don't do it. Please.
但是当然了
But, of course,
纪念品才是推动销量的关键
it was really the souvenirs that were driving trade.
实在是太美了
It was beautiful.
每次你对他处刑后
Every time you finished juicing him,
机器就会吐出有知觉的克莱顿快照
out pops a conscious sentient snapshot of Clayton,
不是录像 而是他思维的真实复制品
not a recording, a true copy of his mind.
永远经历着这美丽的痛苦
perpetually experiencing that beautiful pain.
永远被困在忍受极度痛苦的那一刻
Stuck forever in that one perfect moment of agony.
开关总是拉下
Always on.
永远在受苦
Always suffering.
而且是你所说的
And what you'd call…
袖珍版
fun size.
如果能好受些就坐下吧
Take a seat if it makes it easier.
坐下
Sit down.
怎么了 我的口音吗
What? My accent?
不是英国佬的口音
Not fucking British.
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint.
你是谁
Who are you?
你隐瞒了一部分故事 海恩斯先生 为什么
You left some parts of the story out, Mr. Haynes. Why is that?
你忘了提那些抗议
You forgot to mention the protests.
他的妻子发起了一场运动 吸引了关注
His wife started a campaign, got some momentum behind it.
你会称之为「圣母」的扯淡吧
Guess you'd call it virtue-signaling bullshit,
但我知道这让你的访客量减少了
but I know it hurt your attendance.
后来 抗议者都觉得无聊了
And even the protesters got bored after a while.
因为州政府显然
As soon as it was clear the state.
不打算帮他洗清罪名
wouldn't do a damn thing about clearing him,
他们转向了另一个爆红的司法不公案例
they just moved onto the next viral miscarriage of justice.
好打标签蹭热度
they can hang a hashtag off of.
但他们完成了任务 对吧
But they did their job, right?
这地方上了黑名单
This place was on the shit list.
那之后你的核心顾客群是谁呢
Who was your core clientele after that?
你失去了一日游旅客 游客
You lost the day trippers, the tourists,
家庭访客 还剩谁呢
fun family crowd. Who was left?
又是你 你个一脸死人像的混蛋
You again, you pasty-faced motherfucker?
不合群的人 虐待狂
Loners. Sadists.
极端种族主义疯子
The supremacist sicko demographic.
不不不 出去出去
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Out, out, out.
但这些人还不够多
And that crowd's not big enough.
你依然入不敷出
They don't keep the lights on.
所以如果有人来
So if someone shows up,
典型的种族仇恨的富人 疯狂想要施虐
some classic race-hate rich guy with a hard-on for power…
而他给你一些额外费用让他处刑久一点
and he slips you some extra for a longer time at the crank…
你就欣然接受
you take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
他在那之后就不同了 是吧
Wasn't the same after that, was he?
没有死去 但也不算还活着
Not dead but hardly alive either.
即使变态也不想折磨一个植物人
Even the perverts didn't wanna pull a… a lever on a vegetable.
那还有什么乐趣
Where's the joy in that?
但有人来看过他 对吧
But someone came to see him, right?
她看到了他
She saw him.
她就站在这里
She stood on this spot.
看到你对他做了什么
Saw what you had done to him.
克莱
Clay?
他就像个温顺的动物
He was like a docile animal.
天知道他是否还认得她
God knows if he even recognized her.
天知道他是否还认得我
God knows if he even recognizes me.
爸
Dad.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我妈在那天看到的情景超出了她的承受能力
What my mom saw that day was more than she could take.
她在运动中曾希望能洗刷他的污名
She had hoped during the whole fight to clear his name,
但这让她崩溃了
but that broke her.
你知道她回家后做了什么吗
You know what she did when she came home?
一瓶药 一瓶伏特加
Bottle of pills and a bottle of vodka.
是我发现了她 你这个人渣
I found her. You fucking piece of shit.
是不是很热
Is it hot?
是不是很潮 不好意思
It's humid, right? I'm sorry.
愚蠢的数字空调
Stupid digital AC.
很容易黑掉
Easy to hack.
永远别接受陌生人给的饮料
Never accept drinks from strangers.
我爸教我的
My daddy taught me that.
看你的唇色
Going by the color of your lips,
你30秒之内就会死
you're gonna be gone in 30 seconds.
别担心
Hey, don't worry.
我们会在另一边看到你
We're gonna see you on the other side.
电脑说你醒了
Computer says you're awake.
恭喜你 你是个先驱
Congratulations. You're a pioneer.
你做了什么
What the fuck did you do?
原来将一个新鲜的意识
It turns out that it is possible.
转移到一个虚拟载体里是可行的
to transfer a fresh consciousness inside a virtual one.
我爸要载你一程
My daddy's giving you a ride.
放我出去 你个臭…
Get me out of here, you fucking cun…
我猜你在尖叫着咒骂我
I'm guessing you're screaming and calling me names right now,
但我听不到
but I wouldn't know.
- 你 - 多亏了你 我爸不能说话
- You… - I mean, my dad can't talk, thanks to you.
否则我猜他会转达你的祝福的
Otherwise I'm guessing he'd pass on your goodwill messages.
你个臭婊子 臭婊子
You fu… You fucking bitch! You fucking bitch!
另外 你马上将尝试另一种新体验
In other news, you'll shortly be undertaking another first.
首次双层安乐死
The first double-decker mercy killing.
不不不不不不
No, no, no. No, no, no, no.
我解除了十秒的限制
I took off the ten-second limit.
所以我爸会接受足量的电击
so Daddy'll get a full hit of juice.
应该足够让他解脱了
Should be enough to set him free.
而你
You… however…
海恩斯先生 在他脑内会感同身受
burrowed away inside there, Mr. Haynes, you'll feel it all.
所有的痛苦
All the pain.
- 去死 - 全部完美的电击
- Fuck y… - Every perfect little shot of it.
- 去死 - 我也要给自己做一个纪念品
- Fuck you! - I'm getting myself a souvenir, too.
不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
求你 求你 我
Hey, please, please. I…
开关总是拉下
Always on.
- 永远在受苦 - 妈的 不不不
- Always suffering. - Fuck! No, no, no.
再见 爸爸
Bye, Daddy.
（可取纪念品）
小猴爱你
Monkey loves you.
我做得如何 妈
How'd I do, Mom?
好吗
All good?
好极了 宝贝
Just great, honey.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
谢了
Aw, thanks.